# CARLOS FCO. PARRA GARCÍA

#### SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Professional in the field of mobile development, specialized in Android and iOS systems, with extensive experience in Kotlin and Dart programming languages. I am currently a senior frontend developer, and my daily tasks include the design and development of mobile and web applications using the Flutter framework.



#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER ENTELGY | April 2024 - Present

- Development of a web application using Flutter for a water resources company, optimizing its functionality and user experience.
- Design and development of the business logic and the different user interfaces applying responsive design techniques. API communication with DIO. Implementation of a clean architecture with MVVM, applying Clean Code principles to ensure scalable, maintainable and modular code. State and reactivity management using Provider.
- Working in an Agile (Scrum) environment, using JIRA for project management. Use of GitFlow on GitHub for version control.

# FRONTEND DEVELOPER YOURSTEP | April 2023 - April 2024

- Development of a mobile application using Flutter, which allows students to manage their assignments and exams in a fast and efficient way.
- Integral design and development of the business logic of the application. API communication with DIO. Layout of Figma designs in Flutter, including responsive design. State and reactivity management using BLoC with Cubit.
- Effective project management in an Agile environment (Scrum). Use of GitFlow in GitLab.

#### SOFTWARE AND SYSTEMS DEVELOPER CIBINAR | July 2022 - April 2023

- Development and design of mobile applications with Flutter oriented to intelligent systems of facial detection and recognition. Development of native code (Kotlin and Swift) with Platform Channels. State management using Provider.
- Implementation of Python scripts for load testing of Deep Learning models with TensorFlow and ONNX. Use of OpenCV and NumPy.

## MOBILE DEVELOPMENT INTERNSHIPS CIBINAR | 2021 - 2022

- Development and design of mobile software using the Flutter framework.
- Development of RESTful APIs with Python using Flask, and use of MQTT for IoT systems communication.

#### **CONTACT INFORMATION**

- Phone: +34 644 912 060
- carlosfcoparra@hotmail.com
- GitHub: carlosparra1998

#### LANGUAGES

- English B1 Cambridge.
- Intermediate level of Portuguese.

#### **EDUCATION**

### DEGREE IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

### University of Castilla-La Mancha | 2018 - 2022

- Campollano Foundation Award to the most innovative TFG of the ESII, 2021 2022.
- Honors in TFG, and in the following subjects: Calculus and Numerical Methods, Computer Networks I and Logic.

#### OTHER COMPETENCIES

- Resolving capacity.
- Analysis of complex technical information.
- Social skills.
- Proactivity.
- Time management.